<?xml version="1.0"?>
<metadata xml:lang="en"><Esri><CreaDate>20240305</CreaDate><CreaTime>14250300</CreaTime><ArcGISFormat>1.0</ArcGISFormat><SyncOnce>TRUE</SyncOnce><ModDate>20240502</ModDate><ModTime>18194000</ModTime><scaleRange><minScale>150000000</minScale><maxScale>5000</maxScale></scaleRange><ArcGISProfile>ItemDescription</ArcGISProfile></Esri><toolbox name="CoMMa Data Preparation V1_2" alias="CoMMa_Auxiliaries"><arcToolboxHelpPath>c:\program files\arcgis\pro\Resources\Help\gp</arcToolboxHelpPath></toolbox><dataIdInfo><idCitation><resTitle>CoMMa Data Preparation V1_2</resTitle></idCitation><idPurp>The CoMMa’s Data Preparation includes five tools devoted to data preparation, that are grouped into two toolsets: 
1) Local topographic Position (LTP) derivatives and 2) Pre-processing tools.</idPurp><idAbs>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The CoMMa Toolbox works on DEMs, obtained from multibeam echosounder data or other geophysical and optical instruments (e.g., Lidar, 3D seismic etc.). Datasets may be affected by artefacts that can hinder a correct delineation of the features of interest, for example, vessel motion-related artefacts. A degree of data preparation, such as cleaning the initial data to remove artefacts, could be advised to enhance the performance of both the delineation and characterisation tools. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;T&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;he CoMMa Toolbox includes five tools devoted to data preparation, that can be found within the sub-toolbox CoMMa Data Preparation. These are internally grouped into two toolsets: 1) Local topographic Position (LTP) derivatives and 2) Pre-processing tools.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</idAbs><idCredit>Arosio, R., Gafeira, J. &amp; De Clippele, L. (2024) CoMMa Toolbox - Version 1.2 (https://github.com/ricarosio/CoMMa/tree/main)

Riccardo Arosio (University College Cork) and Joana Gafeira (British Geological Survey) conceived the original idea of the new ArcGIS Pro based on a previous toolbox created by Joana Gafeira, the BGS Seabed Mapping Toolbox (Gafeira, J., 2017). Riccardo Arosio wrote the Python scripts while Joana Gafeira and Laurence De Clippele performed extensive testing.
The tools development was mainly funded by INFOMAR through the Irish Marine Institute’s research grant PDOC 19/08/03. The British Geological Survey and iAtlantic have also supported the creation of the toolbox.</idCredit><searchKeys><keyword>Data Preparation</keyword></searchKeys><resConst><Consts><useLimit>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;CoMMa Toolbox may be freely distributed, modified and used commercially under the terms of its GNU LGPLv3 license.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</useLimit></Consts></resConst></dataIdInfo><distInfo><distributor><distorFormat><formatName>ArcToolbox Toolbox</formatName></distorFormat></distributor></distInfo><mdHrLv><ScopeCd value="005"/></mdHrLv><mdDateSt Sync="TRUE">20240502</mdDateSt></metadata>
