<?xml version="1.0"?>
<metadata xml:lang="en"><Esri><CreaDate>20230907</CreaDate><CreaTime>15561200</CreaTime><ArcGISFormat>1.0</ArcGISFormat><SyncOnce>TRUE</SyncOnce><ModDate>20231008</ModDate><ModTime>20083800</ModTime><scaleRange><minScale>150000000</minScale><maxScale>5000</maxScale></scaleRange><ArcGISProfile>ItemDescription</ArcGISProfile></Esri><toolbox name="CoMMa Delineation" alias="CoMMa_Delineation"><arcToolboxHelpPath>c:\program files\arcgis\pro\Resources\Help\gp</arcToolboxHelpPath></toolbox><dataIdInfo><idCitation><resTitle>CoMMa Delineation</resTitle></idCitation><idPurp>There are two available delineation tools in CoMMa Toolbox, the “Boundary-based” and the “Elements-based” delineation tools. 

“Boundary-based Delineation” tool delineates confined landforms using a DEM or a DEM derivative and focuses on recognising the landform boundary.
“Elements-based Delineation" tool delineates confined landforms by aggregating positive or negative land surface elements (geomorphons).

Both negative and positive features can be mapped using the delineation tools. 
These tools require a set of user-defined thresholds (such as Minimum Vertical Relief, Minimum Width and Minimum Size Ratio) to best delineate the target features.</idPurp><idAbs>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;T&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ere are two available delineation tools in CoMMa, the “Boundary-based delineation” and the “Elements-based delineation” tools. The “Boundary-based delineation” tool can be applied directly to bathymetric DEM and, when the general seascape is otherwise flat, it might be sufficient to isolate and correctly delineate the targeted features. However, this is often not the case, and the interference of sloping topography or other underlying large-scale landforms can distort the signal of the targets. In this case, the “Boundary-based delineation” tool can also use a LTP derivative to isolate a specific wavelength thought to best delineate the feature of interest. The “Elements-based delineation” relies on land surface units created by the geomorphons tool&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</idAbs><idCredit>Arosio, R., Gafeira, J. &amp; De Clippele, L. (2023) CoMMa Toolbox - Version 1.0 (https://github.com/ricarosio/CoMMa/tree/main)

Riccardo Arosio (University College Cork) and Joana Gafeira (British Geological Survey) conceived the original idea of the new ArcGIS Pro based on a previous toolbox created by Joana Gafeira, the BGS Seabed Mapping Toolbox (Gafeira, J., 2017). Riccardo Arosio wrote the Python scripts while Joana Gafeira and Laurence De Clippele performed extensive testing.
The tools development was mainly funded by INFOMAR through the Irish Marine Institute’s research grant PDOC 19/08/03. The British Geological Survey and iAtlantic have also supported the creation of the toolbox.</idCredit><searchKeys><keyword>Feature delineation.</keyword></searchKeys><resConst><Consts><useLimit>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;CoMMa Toolbox may be freely distributed, modified and used commercially under the terms of its GNU LGPLv3 license.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</useLimit></Consts></resConst></dataIdInfo><distInfo><distributor><distorFormat><formatName>ArcToolbox Toolbox</formatName></distorFormat></distributor></distInfo><mdHrLv><ScopeCd value="005"/></mdHrLv><mdDateSt Sync="TRUE">20231008</mdDateSt></metadata>
