<?xml version="1.0"?>
<metadata xml:lang="en"><Esri><CreaDate>20230907</CreaDate><CreaTime>15560900</CreaTime><ArcGISFormat>1.0</ArcGISFormat><SyncOnce>TRUE</SyncOnce><ModDate>20231008</ModDate><ModTime>21030200</ModTime><scaleRange><minScale>150000000</minScale><maxScale>5000</maxScale></scaleRange><ArcGISProfile>ItemDescription</ArcGISProfile></Esri><toolbox name="CoMMa Description" alias="CoMMa_Description"><arcToolboxHelpPath>c:\program files\arcgis\pro\Resources\Help\gp</arcToolboxHelpPath></toolbox><dataIdInfo><idCitation><resTitle>CoMMa Description</resTitle></idCitation><idPurp>The Description tools in CoMMa Toolbox calculate a series of basic geometrical and statistical attributes, additional metrics (such as zonal vector ruggedness and aspect variability index), backscatter statistics and the volume for each shape contained in the delineation shapefile. 
These tools can be used to characterise both features that were mapped automatically or manually mapped.</idPurp><idAbs>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The  &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;CoMMa &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Description Toolset &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;provides the user with three landform description tools that can be run independently from one another and in any order. blocks:   &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Basic Descriptors: Calculates a series of geometrical and statistical attributes for each shape contained in the delineation shapefile.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Texture Descriptors: Calculates a few additional metrics, such as zonal vector ruggedness and aspect variability index, and optionally backscatter statistics. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Volume Descriptor: Calculates the volume and more accurately the height for each shape contained in the delineation shapefile. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</idAbs><idCredit>Arosio, R., Gafeira, J. &amp; De Clippele, L. (2023) CoMMa Toolbox - Version 1.0 (https://github.com/ricarosio/CoMMa/tree/main)

Riccardo Arosio (University College Cork) and Joana Gafeira (British Geological Survey) conceived the original idea of the new ArcGIS Pro based on a previous toolbox created by Joana Gafeira, the BGS Seabed Mapping Toolbox (Gafeira, J., 2017). Riccardo Arosio wrote the Python scripts while Joana Gafeira and Laurence De Clippele performed extensive testing.
The tools development was mainly funded by INFOMAR through the Irish Marine Institute’s research grant PDOC 19/08/03. The British Geological Survey and iAtlantic have also supported the creation of the toolbox.</idCredit><searchKeys><keyword>Feature Characterisation</keyword></searchKeys><resConst><Consts><useLimit>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;CoMMa Toolbox may be freely distributed, modified and used commercially under the terms of its GNU LGPLv3 license.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</useLimit></Consts></resConst></dataIdInfo><distInfo><distributor><distorFormat><formatName>ArcToolbox Toolbox</formatName></distorFormat></distributor></distInfo><mdHrLv><ScopeCd value="005"/></mdHrLv><mdDateSt Sync="TRUE">20231008</mdDateSt></metadata>
